We added the modal, let's make sure we only display it if we are actually buying something, if we did
imdi harekete geir dmesini tkladysak, aslnda bir eyler satn alyor olsaydk,
click the order now button.
yalnzca grntlememizin yolunu izleyelim.
So the modal is included in the burger builder and that's good because the burger builder, we actually
Modem burger reticisine dahil edilir ve bu iyi nk burder Boulder biz aslnda
have our state and that is where we can also determine whether this order now button was clicked or
bizim durumumuz var ve bu da imdi sipari vermiyor olup olmadna karar
not.
verebileceimiz yeri belirleyebilir.
Actually we can't right now
Aslnda u anda bunu yapamayz.
but we can easily add the logic to do so.
Ancak bunu yapmak iin mant kolayca ekleyebiliriz.
For this, I first of all add something to my state,
Bunun iin ncelikle devletime bir eyler ekledim.
I don't only need to know if it is purchasable but if the order now button was clicked.
Yalnzca satn alnabilir olup olmadn bilmem gerekiyor ancak Sipari dmesi tklandnda.
So if we are in purchase mode or something like that.
Satn alma modundaysanz veya byle bir eyse.
So what I want to do is I want to set purchasing to false
Yani yapmak istediim ey, kovalamacann bana geersiz klmak istiyorum.
and of course purchasing should be changed to false once this order now button was clicked.
Ve elbette kovalamaca sahte olarak deitirilmeli, bir kez sipari verin dmeye bir dme tkland.
So I will add a new handler, a new method I'll name it purchaseHandler, purchaseHandler is a normal method
Bu yzden yeni bir ileyici ekleyeceim Yeni bir yntem Ben Chase ileyicisine adn vereceim. Chase ileyicisi bana
and it should be triggered whenever we click this order now button. In there, what I'll do is I will set
normal bir yntem ve her sipariim dmesini tkladmda tetiklenmelidir.
the state of purchasing to true, just like that and I need to pass this to build controls, there is the
Yapacam ite o zaman durumunu ayarlayacam sadece cheesing iin gerek byle ve kontroller ina etmek iin bunu gemek gerekiyor sonunda sonunda
order now button in the end.
sipari dmesi var.
Let's first head to the build controller,
lk nce yerleik denetleyiciye gidelim.
So under build controls, build controls, here we get this button and I want to add a click listener to
Bylece kontrollerin yerleik kabark kontroller altnda burada bu dmeyi edindik ve dmeye bir tklama
the button so onClick which is just a default click listener since this is a default button, there
dinleyicisi eklemek istedim, bylece tklandnda sadece varsaylan bir tklama dinleyicisi var bu varsaylan dmedir.
I want to execute a method which I receive through props and we can choose any prop name we want
Sahibinden aldm bir yntemi uygulamak istiyorum ve istediim pervaneyi seebiliriz.
here, we are right about at setting this up.
Burada bunu ayarlamaya hazrz.
So let's simply name this ordered
yleyse adlandralm sadece sipari etmek.
or something like that.
Ya da byle bir ey.
So I want to execute this
Bu yzden bunu yapmak istiyorum.
and now let's move back to the burger builder which is the place where we have to pass props to build
Ve imdi, Burgert Builder'e geelim; buras, kontrolleri oluturmak iin sahne almak
the controls and here on build controls, I'll add this ordered properly just added and bind it to this purchase
zorunda olduumuz Burgert Builder'e ve tm koyduunuz kontroller dzgn bir ekilde sipari edilmekte ve sadece bu satn alma
handler, so that this method gets executed
ileyicisine balanarak bu metodun altrlmasn salamaktadr.
when we clicked the order now button. Now it's of course nice that we change the state to purchasing,
imdi emir dmesini tkladmzda tabii ki honut kaldk ki bir devlet komutan kovalamay deitirdik.
that alone won't change the way we see the modal though.
Tek bana bu modalz grme biimimizi deitirmeyecektir.
I now could conditionally render this modal, we could add some code to conditionally show or hide the
imdi artl olarak modsal olarak koullu olarak modu gsterip gstermek iin baz kodlar
modal,
ekleyebileceiz.
this would certainly be a way, would be even nicer if we could play a tiny animation on the modal. In
ile hazrlamtk, bizi bu model gsterildiinde yaplan herhangi bir mlk olarak gryoruz.
the modal css file, I already prepared it with the transition css property to simply
Bu, modal C-s'lerde modal zerinde kk bir mation oynayabilirsek, bu kesinlikle daha gzel
animate when this modal is shown.
olurdu, nk bunu eviri geii
So since this is prepared, we should also take advantage of it.
Hazrlandndan beri hepsinden yararlanmalyz.
If we just add or remove the modal from or to the dom, we won't see an animation though, we need to switch
ablondan modal ekleyip kartrsak animasyon grmeyeceiz ancak l canlandrabilmek iin C'yi
some css property to show or hide it, to be able to animate that.
zellik olarak gstermek veya gizlemek zorunda kalacaz.
So let's instead pass a property to modal, the show property maybe, you can choose any name you want
Bunun yerine, gsteri zelliini hareket ettirmek iin bir mlk geelim, belki istediiniz herhangi bir
and bind it to the purchasing state because only if purchasing is true the modal should be visible.
ad seebilir ve satn alma durumuna balayabilirsiniz, nk yalnzca satn alma doruysa motor grnr olmaldr.
Now with that, let's head over to the modal and let's just decode there to change the modal,
imdi bununla birlikte hareketlilie gidelim ve modeli deitirmek iin orada kodu zelim.
depending on the show property. We already have a class here, now
Gsteri mlkinde bekleyen u an burada bir snfmz var.
want to change some inline style, though
Baz satr ii stili de deitirmek istiyorsunuz.
you could also add a new css class and add this class conditionally as we do it in other places
Ayrca, yeni bir A S C snf ekleyebilir ve bu snf, bu uygulamann baka yerlerinde yaptmz
of this application already.
gibi koullu olarak ekleyebilirsiniz.
You're totally free to choose the approach you want but to also practice some inline styles,
stediiniz yaklam semek tamamen yasak fakat ayn zamanda baz satr ii stilleri uygulamakta zgrsnz.
let's bind style here to something dynamic, that dynamic thing should be a javascript object and there, I
Stili buraya dinamik bir eyle balayalm; dinamik eyler bir javascript nesnesi olmal
want to send or set the transform property. If show is true,
ve Show true olduu takdirde transform zelliini gndermek veya ayarlamak istiyorlar.
I'll use ternary expression here,
Burada Tournay ifadesini kullanacam.
if it is true then, the then condition comes after the question mark, I'll set transform to translateY(0)
Doruysa, o zaman o koul, tm evirmeye dntrlen soru iaretinin ardndan gelir.
which is the position I defined in css,
C s S.'de tanmladm pozisyon neden sirrah?
so the position it should really have. If show is not true though,
Dolaysyla gsteri doru deilse D konumu gerekte olmaldr.
I'll set
Her ey hazr.
translateY to minus 100vh, vh is a special unit which refers to the viewport height, so it will
Ekran eksi 100'e evirin h h h h Grnmn yksekliini ifade eden zel bir birimdir, bylece
simply slide it outside of the screen.
ekran yalnzca ekrann dna kaydrrsnz.
I also want to animate the opacity, so let's also set the opacity to something, if props.show is true,
Ayrca Pasotti'nize animasyon yapmak isterim. Bylece, papaannzn gsterisi doruysa, Pasotti'nizi bir eye ayarlamanza izin verir.
it should be one,
Bir tane olmal.
if it's not true,
Eer doru deilse.
so if it's false, it should be 0 so it should be opaque,
Dolaysyla eer sahte ise 0 olmal, bylece opak olmamaldr.
it should be not visible, it should be transparent
ekilebilir olmamal kazanlabilir olmamaldr.
I mean, it should be not visible.
Demek istediim, bu gvenceli olmamal.
So with that, we got that and take advantage of the show property,
Bu yzden bunu aldk ve ov zelliinden faydalanacaz.
save all the files and let's see if this works.
Tm dosyalar sakla ve ie yarayp yarayp yaramadn grelim.
The modal is gone,
Modalist gitti.
let's add some ingredients and click order now,
imdi baz maddeler ekleyin ve imdi tklayn.
we got an error here, cannot read properties set state. Let's head over to the burger builder and to
Burada bir hata var, zelliklerini okuyamayz Ladd'n kafasn burger yapcsna ve kovalayc
the purchase handler, set state
iverene ayarla tarihe ayarla.
and do you have an idea why this failed?
Bunun neden baarsz olduunu dnen var m?
I'm executing this set state here, exactly the same I use in other methods too,
Bu kmeyi burada baka yntemlerde de aynen kullandm gibi uyguluyorum.
why could this fail?
Neden bu baarsz
It fails because of the way I'm creating this method,
olabilir ki bu yntemi oluturduumdan dolay baarsz oluyor.
I use the same method syntax as I use for render but you maybe remember that earlier in the course, I
Ayn yntem szdizimini render iin kullandm gibi kullanyorum, ancak belki daha
mentioned that this syntax will not work correctly,
nce szlmn sz diziminin dzgn almayacan belirttiimi hatrlyorsunuz.
at least if we try to use the this keyword in there if the method is triggered through an event due to
En azndan yntem, bir anahtar kelimenin Javascript'te nasl alt yznden
the way the this keyword works in Javascript, it will then not refer to the class.
bir olaydan tetiklenirse, oradaki bu anahtar kelimeyi kullanmay denersek, snf belirtmez.
This is not the case for remove and addIngredientHandler because I use a slightly different syntax
Reagen ileyicisini kaldrmak ve eklemek iin durum byle deil, nk burada biraz farkl bir szdizimi
there,
kullanyorum.
I set up these methods as properties where I assigned arrow functions.
Bu yntemleri, aero ilevleri olarak atanan zelliklere gre ayarladm.
In the end these are still methods but internally, they take advantage of arrow functions which basically
Sonunda bunlar yine de yntemlerdir ancak itenlikle temel olarak devleti veya ieriini
contain the state or the context of this. So we can easily fix this by setting purchaseHandler equal
ieren havaclk ilevlerinden yararlanrlar; bylece bunu, her bir kovalayc ileyici iin bir ok ilevine eitleyerek kolayca
to an arrow function too and use that syntax for creating the method.
dzeltebilir ve yntemi oluturmak iin stat szdizimini kullanabiliriz .
Now with that, if we save this the error message should not pop up anymore,
imdi bunu kaydedersek, hata mesaj artk almamaldr.
if we now click order now, the modal slides in.
imdi siparii tklarsak modal slaytlar.
So that's looking good,
Bu iyi grnyor.
it's also correctly displaying the state.
Ayrca devlet de doru ekilde grntleniyor.
Now of course it would now be great if we also had a backdrop and if we would click this backdrop,
imdi tabii ki biz de bir zemin vard ve biz zemin olarak tkladysak harika olurdu.
if it then would remove or dismiss the modal.
Eer bu durumda modal kaldrlrsa veya reddedilirse.
Let's work on this over the next lectures.
Bir sonraki derslerde zerinde alalm.